Guide to the Isidor Schneider Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Reznikoff, Charles To: Isidore Schneider, The Bronx, New York, 27 July [n.y.], (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Riding, Laura To: Isidore Schneider, London, England, [ca. July 1928], (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Riding, Laura To: Isidore Schneider, London, England, [ca. July 1928], (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Riding, Laura To: Isidore Schneider, London, England, [ca. July-August 1928], (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rodker, John To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 10 September [1929], (1 p. a.l.s. (with related correspondence)) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore Schneider, York Harbor, Maine, 27 July 1927, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore Schneider, York Harbor, Maine, 14 August 1927, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, York Harbor, Maine, 19 July 1928, (3 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, York Harbor, Maine, 11 September 1928, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, Naples, Italy, 5 April 1929, (3 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, Rome, Italy, 15 May 1929, (1 p. p.c.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, Florence, Italy, 25 may 1929, (6 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul To: Isidore and Helen Schneider, York Harbor, Maine, 27 August 1931, (5 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Isidore Schneider, Old Lyme. Connecticut, 7 August [1972], (1 p. t.l.s. (includes related materials)) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Helen Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. a.l.s. (includes related materials)) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Hedda Rowinski (Mrs. Norman) To: Helen Berlin Schneider (Mrs. Isidor), [n.p.], [n.d.], (5 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, Juneau, Alaska, [n.d.], (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, Juneau, Alaska, [n.d.], (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Mr. & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, [Lincolnvilee Center, Maine], 1 August [n.y.], (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Rosten, Norman To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (written on bottom of letter sent by Scneider)) (Box 2)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], 11 March 1944, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Salzman, Jack To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], 10 Martch 1970, (1 p. t.l.) (Box 2)
  - Sayers, Michael To: Isidor Schneider, Long Island City, 6 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Seldes, George To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], 6 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s. (typed on bottom of letter sent by Schneider)) (Box 2)
  - Sessions, Barbara Foster (Mrs. Roger H.) To: Mr & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, Juziers, [France], 22 August [1928], (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Sessions, Barbara Foster (Mrs. Roger H.) To: Mr & Mrs. Isidor Schneider, Juziers, France, 22 August 1928, (p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Shapiro, Karl To: Isidor Schneider, Gaylordsville, Connecticut, 24 December 1944, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Sheaffer, Louis To: Isidor Schneider, Brooklyn, New York, 14 May [1973], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Sheaffer, Louis To: Isidor Schneider, Brooklyn, New York, 13 December 1973, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Siegmeister, Elie To: Isidor Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 march 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (writen on the bottom of letter sent by Schneider, 1 march 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Siegmeister, Elie To: Isidore Schneider, Ithaca, New York, 27 August 1943, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Slesinger, Tess To: Isidore Schneider, Brooklyn, New York, [1930], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Bernard To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 6 March 1944, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Smith, Harrison To: Isidore Schneider, New York, [n.d.], (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Solomon, Maynard To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 12 December 1974, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Solomon, Maynard To: Helen Schneider, New York, 6 January 1975, (1 p. t.l.s. (inludes related material)) (Box 2)
  - Souppault, Philippe To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, France, 15 February 1927, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Spender, Stephen To: Isidore Schneider, [London], 23 October 1945, (1 p. a.l.s. (with envelope)) (Box 2)
  - Stavis, Barrie To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 20 June 1941, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Stead, Christina Ellen To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 22 October 1941, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Stead, Christina Ellen To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], 7 November 1940, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca, 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l. (written on bottom of letter sent by Schneider, 1 March 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Stevenson, Philip E. To: Isidore Schneider, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 30 September [n.y.], (3 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Taggard, Genevieve To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (2 p. a.l.s. (written on bottom of letter sent by Schneider, 1 March 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Tate, Alan To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (written on bottom of letter sent by Schneider, 1 March 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Torrence, Ridgely To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 18 September 1931, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Trilling, Diana To: Isidore Schneider, Saratoga Springs, New York, 20 June 1931, (4 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Van Doren, Mark To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 9 August 1928, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Van Doren, Mark To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 8 December 1928, (1 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wagner, Charles To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (written on bottom of letter from Schneider, 1 March 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Walsh, Ernest To: Isidore Schneider, Paris, [April 1925], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 8 April 1929, (1 p. t.l.s. (unidentified a.l. on verso to Arthur)) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 12 April 1929, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, [New York], [April 1929], (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, On the Trans-Siberian Rd. east of Omsk, 7 may 1929, (3 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, Tainanfu [China], 7 & 10 June 1929, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, Nanking [China], 17 August 1929, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Mr & Mrs. Isidore Schneider, [New York], 4 May 1930, (1 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Wang, Chi-Chen To: Isidore Schneider, [n.p.], [ca. 1 March 1944], (1 p. a.l.s. (written on top and bottom of letter sent by Schneider, 1 March 1944)) (Box 2)
  - Winters, Yvor To: Isidore Schneider, Palo Alto, 18 May 1928, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Winters, Yvor To: Isidore Schneider, Moscow, Idaho, 30 January 1927, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Winters, Yvor To: Isidore Schneider, Palo Alto, 3 July 1928, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Winters, Yvor To: Isidore Schneider, Palo Alto, 31 May 1929, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Winters, Yvor To: Isidore Schneider, Palo Alto, 15 July 1929, (2 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm To: Isidore Schneider, Greenwich, Conn., 17 July 1928, (2 p. a.l.s. ) (Box 2)
  - Young, Art To: Isidore Schneider, New York, 29 December 1941, (1 p. Christmas card) (Box 2)
  - Zara, Louis To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, Illinois, 29 December 1941, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Farrar and Rinehart To: Isidore Schneider, Chicago, Illinois, 14 July 1930, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - [?] To: [Isidore Schneider], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [unknown rejection letter for Earth is Your Apple]
- Series II: Inscribed Books
  - Millen Brand: Savage Sleep; -- Stanley Burnshaw: Early and Late Testament; -- Louis Grudin: The Outer Land and Other Poems; -- Matthew Josephson: Jean-Jaques Rousseau (Box 3)
  - The following are all by Norman Rosten: Under the Boardwalk --The Big Road --The Plane and the Shadow --Mister Johnson (based on the novel by Joyce Cary) --Come Slowly, Eden --Thrive Upon the Rock --The Fourth Decade and other Poems --Songs for Patricia --Return Again, Traveler (Box 3)
- Series III: Notebook and Manuscripts
  - The Wall Within:. Uncompleted manuscript of a book on neurosis and art; a project begun under the auspices of the Postgraduate Center for Psychotherapy -- The Functions of Literature: (manuscript of work in progress;) -- Manuscripts, published and unpublished -- Newspaper clipping of various reviews of I. Schneider's work in various periodicals: 1934-36 -- Manuscripts of short stories, including some intended for popular periodicals (Box 4)
- Series IV: Manuscript and Reviews
  - Printed Reviews of I. Schneider's Work -- Reviews by Schneider in, Saturday Review, New Republic, N.Y. Sun, N.Y. Times, N.Y. World and N.Y. Telegram, N.Y. Herald Tribune, N.Y. Post, The Nation, Menorah Journal. -- Other related miscellaneous articles and reviews. -- Unpublished Schneider m.s. The Hand (Box 5)
- Series V: Books Relating to Schneider
  - Farewell to Walden by Florence Becker (inscribed) -- Inky Darling by Louis Grudin (inscribed) -- Poets Gold by David Ross -- Cross Section edited by Edwin Seaver (inscribed) -- The Permanent Goethe edited by Thomas Mann (inscribed) -- Mark Twain: Social Critic by Philip S. Foner (inscribed) -- Man in the Mirror by Aaron Schmuller (inscribed) -- The Autobiography of Emanuel Carnevali compiled by Kay Boyle -- Stefansson Prophet of the North by Earl P. Hanson(inscribed) -- The Spider and the Clock by S. Funaroff (inscribed) -- The Nassau Review (A play about Emily Dickenson) (Box 6)
- Series VI: Book Find Club Book Reports
  - Typed and autograph brief book reports, A - F, Before 1962 (Box 7)
  - Typed and autograph brief book reports, G - N, Before 1962 (Box 8)
  - Typed and autograph brief book reports, A - L, Before 1962 - 1967 (Box 10)
  - Typed and autograph brief book reports, M - Z, Before 1962 - 1967 (Box 11)
- Series VII: Manuscripts by I. Schneider
  - The Kingdom of Necessity in the author's hand -- -- An autograph fragment of The Judas Time -- -- Autograph manuscript of unpublished novel: Earth is your Apple (pages 1-51 missing) -- -- Part of an unpublished untitled and unfinished novel, typed (Box 12)
- Series VIII: Books with Contributions by I. Schneider
  - Cross Section 1944 Edited by Edwin Seaver -- -- Cross Section 1945 Edited by Edwin Seaver -- -- The American Caravan Edited by Van Wyck Brooks, Lewis Mumford, Alfred Kreymborg and Paul Rosenfeld -- -- Reader's Digest 1966 Almanac -- -- A Golden Treasury of Jewish Literature Edited by Leo W. Schwarz -- -- The Twin Bedside Anthology (in "His" and "Hers" editions) Edited by Charles Lee -- -- War Poems of the United Nations Edited by Joy Davidman (Box 13)
- Series IX: Collected Books and Journals
  - Jean Reynaud: Encyclopediste de l'epoque Romantique (inscribed), by David Albert Griffiths -- -- A Treasury of Jewish Poetry edited by Nathan and Marynn Ausubel -- -- The Autobiography of Maxim Gorky translated by I. Schneider -- -- A copy of Publisher's Weekly 18 January 1947 containing an article by I. Schneider on the book trade -- -- Caravan IV Edited by Alfred Kreymborg, Lewis mumford and Paul Rosenfeld (Box 14)
  - Sonnets and Ballate by Guido Cavalcanti, translated by Ezra Pound -- -- Dynamo, A Journal of Revolutionary Poetry January 1934, includes a poem by I. Schneider: "Mister Comrad" -- -- Dynamo, A journal of Revolutionary Poetry Summer1934, includes a poem by I. Schneider, "Young Revolutionist;" -- -- Alcestis: A Poetry Quarterly July 1935, Includes I. Schneider poem: "In the New York Public Library" -- -- 1924 Contains short story "A Marriage of Venus" -- -- Collected Poems by James Joyce -- -- More Poems A. E. Housman -- -- The Poeple, Yes By Carl Sandburg -- -- My Childhood by Maxim Gorky, translated by I. Schneider -- -- Vladimir Mayakovsky 1894 - 1930 The American Quarterly on the Soviet Union -- -- The Measure:A Journal of Poetry January 1922, includes "My Street" by I. Schneider -- -- Robert Kaufman (a retrospective on the work of the modern artist, Kaufman, 1913 - 1959) -- -- The Judas Time by I. Schneider -- -- Smoke and Steel by Carl Sandburg -- -- Doctor Transit by I. Schneider with an inscription to his wife, Helen -- -- Comrade Mister poems by I. Schneider, includes m.s poem, typed by I. Schneider -- -- The Temptation of Anthony by I. Schneider (Box 15)
  - The Experience of Love compiled and edited by I. Schneider -- -- The American Caravan 1927 edited by: Van Wyck Brooks; Lewis Mumford, Alfred Kreymborg and Paul Rosenfeld -- -- American Writers Congress edited by Henry Hart -- -- The Enlightenment: The Culture of the Eighteenth Century edited and introduced by Isidore Schneider -- -- From the Kingdom of Necessity by I. Schneider (Box 16)
  - Marxism and Art essays selected by Maynard Solomon, (inscribed to I. Schneider) -- -- Catholicism edited by George Brantl -- -- Proceso en Diciembre by Emilio Diaz Valcarcel -- -- This Was Radio By Joseph Julian, inscribed to Isidore and Helen Schneider -- -- O'Neill, Son and Playwright by Louis Sheaffer, inscribed to Isidore Schneider -- -- African Sculpture Speaks by Ladislas Segy, inscribed to Isidore Schneider -- -- Marilyn: an Untold Story by Norman Rosten, inscribed to Isidore and Helen Schneider (Box 17)
- Series X: Articles and Reviews
  - Articles and reviews for New Masses 1936 - 1948; The Nation; New Republic; Soviet Russia Today (Box 18)
- Series XI: Book Reports for George Braziller
  - Alphabetized book reports in brief., 1972 - 1975 (Box 19)
- Series XII: Book Reports for George Braziller and Grove Press
  - Alphabetized book reports in brief., 1967 - 1971 (Box 20)